Ajay
that every film is like this from the beginning, I
welcome Sumit Bandariya,
thank you very much for watching this video.
Today our topic is important
feeling statement
that when a person is buying a policy,
he goes on Google and gets
information from his friends, so after a few days of
hard work of 15 days, he gets to know the
information, this is called
plain settlement ratio, claim settlement
ratio is calculated that how many claims this company has
settled, if to take that
job, it means a person understands that
if a low flame comes then 9300 will be settled, right now
all have been cancelled
and now is this figure important or
not, so I will
talk on three points, this data is
in real time i.e. as of today's date,
within 2021, the Director of India Center, that
anywhere the
number two appointed on the data public, defining the claim settlement ratio of any company within today's date
What is the formula? How many claims have been settled,
how many are in the pipeline and are about to be
settled, or policies of which side,
that claim settlement ratio
is the central part, the policies remaining through the bank, those
policies, these are different from retail policies,
you have talked about online policies, so are
all these policies covered under that ratio or are there only
some policies in it, thirdly, this
ratio that we are seeing, normally a 12 year
old house data network is available on it, what is the
composition of this ratio, what does the ratio mean
when I am comparing two things, for example, if
I compare two vehicles and
check their average, then
naturally it is a simple concept, well, in any
way I list
how many
meters in 1 liter, this grade teacher is given, so I will try to cover
one side of the road in the same type
of weather, then the
comparison of both the things, you call it standard
condition, now there is a thing on top of this that
why do we have to worry about this, what number do we have to
worry about, let me take an
example, there is a company which is 20 year
old sports  Glass will take a policy of 20 lakhs
and out of that 10% claims will be
rejected, that is around 2 lakhs,
18 lakh claims out of 20 lakhs were rejected and two
Laxman Jacques Rogge, another company came just 4 years
ago, its claim settlement ratio is
98%, otherwise
now no, but it had protested for
this, which are 5 lakhs, out of 5 lakh
policies 5% will be rejected, so
this one company is only doing group work, the
second company is bank probationary, this third one is better, do it
directly online through call center, which IT company, how do
you set up all the work, but when two things have to be
compared, we
cannot compare them, so whenever a
statistician analyzes anything, the
concept for that is
sample data, that is, dry ginger and I took out two pieces from
different lots, dated them
or some piston came to me, I am
checking them, so there are thousand questions, so
from them I took out two pieces randomly,
but in every slot
How many should be taken out of this, only two,
this should be from the sample size, so the ratio
is a word that the company whose
sunscreen is on Saturday,
with whose association, then within this, the note of any company,
now my guarantee is that I will go to those
10% of those whose claims have been settled, so
within one and a half to two years, ghee from this, so
my own personal experience by
subscribing and we have real time, so on
this remedy, we have done
our work, the regulator will
see that our work has been done, how do we
establish that our
claim should not be rejected in any company, so have I placed an
emphasis on it, so the important thing is that I have to
take the best possible policy
and after paying money in that policy, my
claim should not be rejected, what do I have to do for this,
first I have to
set my need base channel, I have to set my executive
that what I want, then from all these
policies available in India,
we will choose from four-five policies
that this is the most
suitable policy for me, the second step which is very  It
is important, pay online or take it offline by
going to someone's house, you need
someone good to buy it for you. The way
you buy the policy decides whether you will get
your claim or not. So,
twenty-five years ago, a female had a
caesarean operation, was it
necessary to tell her? It was not necessary because if
a person had TV or symptoms for 10 days, then
her infection would be cured. If
a person had complete dad treatment
50 years ago, then is it related to
telling this? No, join the
rate. So, we already have to tell you about
any kind of hormonal disorder or
medicine during pregnancy. You have again the
questions that the company has asked you and we will give
you every answer,
subscribe and like. Mostly, there may be trouble in it regarding
time or after that, the
alarm may come early, so much haste
and then later, you will get it well,
only that much effort will have to be put in on the time, so do it a
minute earlier or a minute later,
then the same point, the way we
talk about this simple thing, this  I will give a
thousand times more MB to this parameter, to this question, to this system. Let's compare the claim
settlement ratio. The subject of claim settlement ratio will be
made with that ratio.
Hello, hello, I have been working with a company for years, I am doing
one thing, I am doing one thing online, do
one option work, what will
we compare it with, this is how I will
get the policy, the way in which the position will go, have I
even written the proposal form of the company or not, have I read the
policy terms and conditions of the company 21 times,
these things matter a thousand times,
these things are a small element, claim
settlement ratio, so see, you may
like my point, you may not like it,
I can share my practical experience on this
thing, you have to judge a lot of things, you
need the office of that company, if you have
time, go to the consumer court and see, you will
find that the claims settlement of this company is
not going well there,
okay, you will be surprised, all the
companies will do it, then  Here, the
21 most important people in this policy are the one
who is
making the policy and the one who is buying the policy,
both of them have performed their duty and their religion
i.e. their responsibility very well, so
you will see on camera that if
both of them, anywhere in the world, have made
some mistake for any reason, then the
company will measure which company, what is its ratio,
how old is the company, then the
claim got rejected, I again say the same thing,
you will get the claim again and again, if it gets
rejected then it will
not be the same result in all the companies,
this idea has worked very well, it is the
standard of the entire process, it has been
calibrated, the question of giving the claim has been
standardized, it is a
regulated product, then on this thing
I repeatedly give the reason that the
bribe that can be taken, it might be something important,
academic leave, but property
price
unity may arise, but I do
not put too much emphasis on this thing, then
I will have such tension which you people may have  It
is requested that you always
read the terms and conditions of the policy. Always download the
proposal form of your policy from the insurance company's
website and read it.
What does anyone tell you about the last date?
If you have to do it in a hurry, then do it
next year. Do
not be in a hurry. Any hasty action will ultimately cause
you trouble. If
you have to review any policy, then do it a
few minutes before the policy expires. If you have to do portability,
which you had processed earlier, do not
use it at the last moment and take
any decision in a hurry. People make mistakes, there are
many mistakes. For example, a
gentleman
contacted us for consistency and said that we have a notification. I
checked with him. I told him
how old is the policy, whether it has been in operation in one company or
in another company for 2 years. If
you have
checked my first parameters, then have you done the same for the last 10
years? Then your
bike cannot be bought from the policy.
Portability has been left out. The one you have bought is
wrong, so proposal.  When I
downloaded the form and checked it, I found that
half of the proposal form was eaten and the person did
not know that the details were filled in it, so
now they are educated people, it must be a mistake,
I am not blaming them
but I am just trying to give you an example
that where the person who is restless,
where the cream was unfair or
intentional, but the policy would be wrong, how about
another one, but the
policy from your absolutely non-person, rest of the time it
is possible that two people took one in between and make a mistake
for the other, otherwise there would be a limit on the
policy, at this time the company might cry, they should
examine it, in
2016-15, someone had undergone a
small operation or surgery treatment,
he forgot to inform the company, now the person in a
positive, he is a member of the family, he is
in the information, so how did he commit the mistake, it was a mistake, he did
not have the information, he did not have the knowledge, here I am
emphasizing on this thing that it is
important to tell what the company asked, what is someone from the call center
saying, what is someone of ours saying about the
information result  All the external
things, look at our Roti form,
you will know yourself, all the questions have to be answered,
so now in both the policies, there was
an online error and one offline, so
whose fault is it,
hello, hello, so now how are these two, in which
this mistake happened, the second
policy period is about to end, I did
not get the next one, I got it for the first policy,
now where is this issue, now whatever has been
addressed somewhere, now what do I have to do
with the claim settlement ratio of the company, another
pigmentation works for crores, what is
going on in my house, my policy was
talked about wrongly, what is its
settlement ratio of that organization, has there been no link from the embassy, ​​so
every time
I come across such a thing, you should like the policy,
review it, do portability,
no, if there is nothing then
do it with a little caution, do not be hasty, if
any of you think that you should get
all this information readymade, then
it is totally free of cost, in this YouTube
video we have ordered our  I have given
links to sixty-seventy videos, you
should find them inside, you will
get all the information free of cost, you
should talk to the policy person, what things should be kept in
mind, how are the results clean,
dig in the Play Store and
our video is made quite high in a proposal form,
secondly if you want some then
subscribe to many more of our videos without any hassle, if
you do not have time, then
this can be done, otherwise you can click on our video,
if we try to give you this message
that the proposal form is very
important, the policy terms and conditions are
very important, then like this video,
share it and subscribe on social media
quickly, so do a little to the channel so that the
information
reaches as many people as possible, we fulfill our duty, if
you liked it then you
participated in it, so
you watched this video, you took out time, then finally if you
liked it then subscribe to this channel so
that it is your wish, you took out time to
watch this video, thank you
very much, thank you very much, Vande
Mataram has happened